# Laura Zodrow

## Front-End JavaScript Developer

Denver, Colorado

832.922.2053

laura.zodrow@gmail.com

### **ABOUT**

I am seeking a front-end web developer position. I have roughly three years of experience creating websites and applications, and have developed strong skills for design and UI-based development. About two years ago, I completed a full-stack Javascript-based web development boot-camp and am looking for a position that will challenge me to improve the skills I learned while getting to play with the cutting-edge tools that are developing in the Javascript ecosystem.

## SKILLS



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer

ReadyTalk - Denver, CO

December 2015 - Current

Currently creating a checkout portal for our newest product FoxDen. Using React, Node, Express, and making third party calls to Recurly's api. Created the FoxDen website using Phenomic, a modern website generator based on the React and Webpack ecosystem. Also, worked with our back-end engineers to set up the deployment pipeline (using Jenkins, Docker, and AWS). View the site

o https://foxden.io/

#### Web Developer

Black Dog Digital - Denver, CO

February 2015 - December 2015

Develop Wordpress websites, including a project using component based techniques. Create custom Wordpress themes, using HTML5 and CSS3 to implement design specs. Use jQuery to do DOM manipulation and attach event handlers. Write client side PHP scripts making database calls and doing data manipulation. Lead Developer on

- o http://www.spindenver.com
- http://www.threetomatoesitaly.com

#### Web Developer

Roots Elementary - Denver, CO

January 2015 - June 2015

Collaborated to create scheduling and student monitoring application for Roots Elementary, Charter School in Denver, CO. Implemented client side Google OAuth and integrated with Google calendar API. Also, integrated with third party scanning software. Application uses ¡Query, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, and Web Sockets.

## Web Developer Apprentice

RefactorU - Boulder, CO

Attended a 10-week intensive programming boot camp learning both front-end and back-end web development, with a focus on JavaScript applications. Completed numerous class assignments, including a final class project:

Chronicles Abroad, an app that helps organize and document the incredible experiences people enjoy
while traveling or taking classes abroad. Users of the app can easily organize mementos of their travels
and also search through a database that discusses schools and programs abroad and provides detailed
information and reviews on pubs, hostels, museums, and much more in various countries.

## Freelance Web Designer and Developer

Houston, TX + Boulder, CO

October 2013 - Present

Design and develop the websites for gallery owner Edgar Medina in Houston, TX and Fine Art Associates in Boulder, CO (the latter using a custom Wordpress theme).

- View Edgar Medina's Gallery: http://www.medinaedgar.com
- View Fine Art Associates Gallery: http://www.faaboulder.com

## Assistant Product Manager

September 2012 - December 2013

September 2014 - November 2014

AA Concepts - Houston, TX

Created the graphics for the Langford Market website, developing my interest in web design and development. Also booked, directed, and styled Langford Market photo shoots, and assisted the Brand Manager in planning and executing all marketing and promotional events.

## **Gallery Assistant**

September 2011 - December 2012

michelle y williams - Houston, TX

Designed ads and artwork promotional slips for opening events. Built client relationships for current and future art sales. Also, represented the company at art fairs, both domestically and internationally.

# **EDUCATION**

RefactorU: 10-week Full-Stack JavaScript Development course Bachelor of Arts: Austin College, Sherman, TX (Graduated May 2011)

- o Major in Political Science; Minor in Italian Studies
- International Educational Studies, Rome, Italy (2009–2010)